<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Parameter Estimation on Project notebook for the Invasion Heterogeneity project</title>
    <link>/InvasionHet/categories/parameter-estimation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Parameter Estimation on Project notebook for the Invasion Heterogeneity project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/InvasionHet/categories/parameter-estimation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Likely-looking distributions</title>
      <link>/InvasionHet/2018/11/14/likely-looking-distributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/InvasionHet/2018/11/14/likely-looking-distributions/</guid>
      <description>Let’s think about which distributions could be good. We know what the (half-)normal, exponential, and log-normal look like.
Nathan et al. (2012) also suggest:
 Exponential power 2Dt Inverse power Logistic Mixture models Inverse Gaussian (Wald) Wiebull Gamma  The scaling factors in Nathan et al. are for two-dimensional dispersal expressed in radial distance (I think). They suggest that this can be converted to a “distance kernel” by multiplying by \(2\pi r\), but that doesn’t seem right for e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rmutil and fitdistrplus</title>
      <link>/InvasionHet/2018/10/22/rmutil-and-fitdistrplus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/InvasionHet/2018/10/22/rmutil-and-fitdistrplus/</guid>
      <description>Warning in .check.version(config): Your configuration is compatible with version 0.8 of the ProjectTemplate package. Please run ProjectTemplate::migrate.project() to migrate to the installed version 0.8.2. So the fix I did last week to computegetparam() (to allow “y” as an argument to the distribution functions) does allow fitdist to work (sort of) with the rmutil distributions. However, there can still be failures in estimatation or SE calculation, because there are a number of other ways that the rmutil distributions work differntly from the base distribution functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with fitdistrcens</title>
      <link>/InvasionHet/2018/10/18/working-with-fitdistrplus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/InvasionHet/2018/10/18/working-with-fitdistrplus/</guid>
      <description>Warning in .check.version(config): Your configuration is compatible with version 0.8 of the ProjectTemplate package. Please run ProjectTemplate::migrate.project() to migrate to the installed version 0.8.2. So here’s what happens if we try to run fitdistrcens on a non-standard distribution:
library(rmutil) temp &amp;lt;- filter(disperseLer, ID == &amp;quot;100_0&amp;quot;) cens_data &amp;lt;- cens_dispersal_data(temp, 7) try(fitdistcens(cens_data, &amp;quot;ggamma&amp;quot;, start = list(s = 5, m = 4, f = 2)), outFile = stdout()) Error in checkparamlist(arg_startfix$start.arg, arg_startfix$fix.arg, : argument &amp;quot;hasnodefaultval&amp;quot; is missing, with no default Does it work with fitdist, which doesn’t account for the censoring?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fitdistrplus</title>
      <link>/InvasionHet/2018/10/04/fitdistrplus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/InvasionHet/2018/10/04/fitdistrplus/</guid>
      <description>Warning in .check.version(config): Your configuration is compatible with version 0.8 of the ProjectTemplate package. Please run ProjectTemplate::migrate.project() to migrate to the installed version 0.8.2. I’ve modified the helper functions to separate out the creation of the censored data frame from the fitting, and to allow setting the origin. Note that setting zero = 7 only looks at the runway, and allows use of non-truncated distributions when the distribution only has support for non-negative values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting plans, and wrestling with seed stochasticity</title>
      <link>/InvasionHet/2017/10/23/revisiting-plans-and-wrestling-with-seed-stochasticity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/InvasionHet/2017/10/23/revisiting-plans-and-wrestling-with-seed-stochasticity/</guid>
      <description>Focus on Ler? As I look at various pieces of the model (which I’ve started to assemble in lib/model.R), I realize that there are a sufficient number of ways in which the RIL data are different (and not yet analyzed) that I may find it challenging to exactly mirror the Ler model. In particular, I’m going to find it rather challenging (I think) to estimate the environmental stochasticity in seed production among generations and replicates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ler kernel heterogeneity</title>
      <link>/InvasionHet/2017/09/22/ler-kernel-heterogeneity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/InvasionHet/2017/09/22/ler-kernel-heterogeneity/</guid>
      <description>The next steps in the Ler dispersal analysis are to confirm statistical support for among-rep heterogeneity and see if the kernel parameters are correlated with the fraction dispersing.
Housekeeping Added the functions for the truncated distributions and to fit the models to lib/helpers.R.
 Kernel heterogeneity The total AIC for the rep-specific fits was 58230.28 and 58366.17 for the normal and lognormal models, respectively.
I think that if I pass the whole data set to the analysis function it will combine all the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fit Ler dispersal kernels</title>
      <link>/InvasionHet/2017/09/19/fit-ler-dispersal-kernels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/InvasionHet/2017/09/19/fit-ler-dispersal-kernels/</guid>
      <description>File to load Ler dispersal data Here is the new file data/disperseLer.R:
### Creates the data object disperseLer, representing the Ler dispersal experiment # Get data from Jenn&amp;#39;s file data_dir &amp;lt;- &amp;quot;~/Dropbox/Arabidopsis/analysis&amp;quot; disperseLer &amp;lt;- read.csv(file.path(data_dir, &amp;#39;2013_08_08_Exp1_Spray.csv&amp;#39;), header = TRUE) # Drop the &amp;quot;clipped&amp;quot; treatment disperseLer &amp;lt;- droplevels(subset(disperseLer, new_trt != &amp;quot;clipped&amp;quot;, drop = TRUE)) # Drop the columns with the (irrelevant) info about where the mom pots came from disperseLer &amp;lt;- disperseLer[, -c(1:4, 6)] # Clean up column names names(disperseLer) &amp;lt;- c(&amp;quot;ID&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Pot&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Distance&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Seedlings&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Siliques&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Density&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Treatment&amp;quot;) # Make some factor variables disperseLer$ID &amp;lt;- as.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitting dispersal kernels</title>
      <link>/InvasionHet/2017/09/13/fitting-dispersal-kernels/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/InvasionHet/2017/09/13/fitting-dispersal-kernels/</guid>
      <description>Quick looks at dispersal. Lewis et al 2008 show how to calculate empirical moment generating functions, but I’m not sure how useful that is for us. Nathan et al. 2012 has a good review of kernels, but not much statistical info. I found Viana et al. 2016 which suggests fitting the CDF is better than fitting the PDF.
Viana also led my to the fitdistrplus package, which fits standard distributions. I think this is what we need–I was increasinglyl unconfident im my home-rolled fitting routines.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>