<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Project notebook for the Invasion Heterogeneity project</title>
    <link>https://brucekendall.github.io/InvasionHet/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Project notebook for the Invasion Heterogeneity project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://brucekendall.github.io/InvasionHet/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying out BlogDown</title>
      <link>https://brucekendall.github.io/InvasionHet/2017/09/29/trying-out-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brucekendall.github.io/InvasionHet/2017/09/29/trying-out-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m trying out blogdown (https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/) for serving up the project notebook. Advantages:
 Rebuilds only update changed files Dialog box for creating new posts Automatically shows posts in date order, presumably even if they&amp;rsquo;ve been edited Might be possible to automate serving it up on the github page, so Jenn can just look at it in a web browser  (Potential) Disadvantages:
 Whole new file structure to figure out (in particular, I may have to modify the knitr option for setting the working directory, which was based on a relative path) Presumably I can set up the post creation script to include my ProjectTemplate preamble, but that will take work/trial and error I will have to figure out how caching works with this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback from Jenn</title>
      <link>https://brucekendall.github.io/InvasionHet/2017/10/03/feedback-from-jenn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brucekendall.github.io/InvasionHet/2017/10/03/feedback-from-jenn/</guid>
      <description>Jenn has sent a couple of emails in response to last spring’s work:
September 29 Here’s some feedback on thhe Key Results (from June). More on Monday!
 Silique number does not seem to be a good proxy for the number of seeds actually released (e.g., p. 153)
 I’m not sure where to go with this. Seems like there could be several explanations - either the siliques opened with a lot of variability, there’s more variation in seeds/silique than we estimated, or some seeds are much more viable than others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model planning</title>
      <link>https://brucekendall.github.io/InvasionHet/2017/10/02/model-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brucekendall.github.io/InvasionHet/2017/10/02/model-planning/</guid>
      <description>Conceptual overview The model has two fundamental steps:
Seed production Seed dispersal  Seed production is density dependent, with a Gompertz deterministic skeleton: \[\begin{equation} \log(S_{g,t,x}) = a_g + b_g \log(N_{g,t,x}), \end{equation}\] where \(S\) is seed number and \(N\) is adult number; \(g\) is genotype, \(t\) is generation and \(x\) is location. In addition, there is demographic stochasticity (probably Poisson, but need to check); temporal environmental stochasticity; and among-replicate environmental stochasticity. Need to check how well correlated the latter are among RILs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customizing blogdown</title>
      <link>https://brucekendall.github.io/InvasionHet/2017/09/30/customizing-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brucekendall.github.io/InvasionHet/2017/09/30/customizing-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>I am now on my computer at home; after updating packages and rstudio, and installing blogdown and hugo, everything is running fine (although I still need to update my ~/.Rprofile).
Tags and categories Getting links to tags and categories was as simple as editing the menu section of config.toml; the one trick is to add weight variables to get the order I want (the default is alphabetical). Here is the relevant bit of code:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Directional dispersal in Ler</title>
      <link>https://brucekendall.github.io/InvasionHet/2017/09/29/directional-dispersal-in-ler/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brucekendall.github.io/InvasionHet/2017/09/29/directional-dispersal-in-ler/</guid>
      <description>The correlation between the fraction dispersing and the mean dispersal distance of the dispersers could be mean one of two things:
Simulated rain that makes more seeds go makes them go further in all directions Simulated rain that makes more seeds go is pushing them in the direction of the receiving runway  This matters because in case 2, the dispersal kernel in the negative direction will, presumably, have its absolute mean reduced.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>